<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Dedalus Dreams</title><link href="https://davidwangz137.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://davidwangz137.github.io/feeds/experimental.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://davidwangz137.github.io/</id><updated>2016-11-18T10:33:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Reading other People's blogs</title><link href="https://davidwangz137.github.io/reading-other-peoples-blogs.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-18T10:33:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-11-18T10:33:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Zhiyuan Wang</name></author><id>tag:davidwangz137.github.io,2016-11-18:reading-other-peoples-blogs.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've started reading more blogs in order to find out what would be good content for me to put and not create posts which are copies or worse (like Pareto efficient worse) than the posts which currently exist on the internet. I believe it is much better to link those posts. The effects of writing the exact same post can be done better by other means. For example if I have an opinion on a topic and was going to write almost point for point the same post that somebody else had on the topic, it might be better for me to link to the post and hae commentary to specific points and built upon the arguments made. This allows me to refer back to the original post as a reference but also have my own post for my own viewpoint and why I feel that way (my intuition). After all, creating things is very energy intensive. If it is already there then finding a way to use it so that it becomes a part of your intuition (though probably not as much as if you derived it yourself, but still deep enough that you can apply it well) doesn't take up as much effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also by reading other blogs I get a sense for what things are good to post. I see some posts which make me cringe and I would rather not post things like those (or too many. This post is pretty cringe-worthy currently).&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Hello World!</title><link href="https://davidwangz137.github.io/hello-world.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-17T09:12:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-11-17T09:12:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Zhiyuan Wang</name></author><id>tag:davidwangz137.github.io,2016-11-17:hello-world.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've finally decided to go to blog format website and just use a library to handle all the bloggin instead of implementing my own. That would be fun but I feel like dedicating my time to other pursuits would be more interesting and be better since I'm not going to be a web developer. Saying that, back to work. I'm going to post a few things here and now about what I'm currently doing and some thoughts I have. I keep a journal so I'll try to only write insightful things. I might add a comment system later so people to comment on what I write (and point out my glaring errors/fallacies) but that is for another time.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>